welcome back to AP US History in under 3
minutes no time for intros let's get
into it so the revolution is over the
question is what effect did it have on
society well one of the things often
glossed over about the revolution is
that there were calls for abolition of
slavery hence garning the name abolition
movement the reason for this was because
of increased awareness of inequalities
in society and of course the
enlightenment which caused people like
Anthony benaz before and through the
revolution to continue writing books
calling for the abolition of slavery it
did end up working but only in little
States like Pennsylvania where they
passed an act for the gradual abolition
of slavery which gradually got rid of
slavery in Pennsylvania this was the
first Act of its kind and set a
precedent for future abolitionist
movements there were also many other
abolition movements in other Northern
Territories like Massachusetts women
played crucial roles in the revolution
often working as nurses seamstresses and
managing households in their husband's
absence this increased participation
along with Enlightenment inspired
feminism orchestrated by Enlightenment
thinker Mary Wilston craft caused women
to call for more expanded roles in
society Abigail Adams in a letter to
John Adams pleaded for him to remember
the ladies and Judith Murray and her on
the equality of the Sexes used Theology
and reason to explain the equality of
men and women this would lead to a
growing idea of Republican Motherhood
which called on women to teach
Republican values within the family and
granted women a new importance in
American political culture however women
wouldn't start getting true rights until
the first W feminism of the mid 19th
century and last thing to note is the
American revolution's effect on the rest
of the world debt caused by the American
Revolution along with many other reasons
caused France to go through a radical
bloody Revolution Haiti being inspired
by the American Revolution and a lot of
other reasons caused a slave rebellion
in which they won and once again the
influence of the American Revolution was
a factor in causing a series of
revolutions throughout Latin America and
though each of these revolutions had
their own modum of reasons for breaking
out the fact is the American Revolution
and its influence is a reason for each
one on the screen now are AP stock
questions for this topic pause
now I'll put the answers on the screen
no
see you in the next one